Phone: (+44) 07910-390 599 Webpage: <a href="http://www.hentula.com">http://www.hentula.com</a> Email: <a href="joakim.hentula@gmail.com">joakim.hentula@gmail.com</a>

Joakim Hentula 8a Church Lane CV32 7JT Leamington Spa, Warwickshire United Kingdom

# Curriculum Vitae - Joakim Hentula

## **Objective**

Creating great games, working with talented people.

### **Profile**

A programmer with five years of professional games development experience. Disciplined, hard working and with a knack for problem solving. Does not back down from a challenge and is able to learn, understand and apply new technologies in a well organized and efficient manner

A naturally supportive team-player who has been told he's a great teacher. Positive, creative, listens well and most of all eager to work with and learn from talented people making great games.

## **Expertise**

- C++ (9 years)
- C# (3 years)
- Python (3 years)
- Audio programming (in-house and AudioKinetic Wwise)
- Multi platform development: Xbox 360, PS3, GamesForWindows, Steam, including TRC/TCR compatability
- Tools development (developed in house real time object editor)
- Network, RakNet and in-house solution (developed game level network serialisation)
- Physics, ODE and in-house solution
- Perforce
- Has experience in various audio (Ableton Live, Cubase) and visual suites (Photoshop, Blender3D, 3DS Max)

### **Professional experience**

2011-2012, Codemasters, Audio programmer - GRID 2
 Created new audio mark up tool with real time in game editing, assisted in integrating 3rd party audio middleware.

Phone: (+44) 07910-390 599 Webpage: <a href="http://www.hentula.com">http://www.hentula.com</a> Email: <a href="joakim.hentula@gmail.com">joakim.hentula@gmail.com</a>

Joakim Hentula 8a Church Lane CV32 7JT Leamington Spa, Warwickshire United Kingdom

- 2010-2011, Codemasters, Audio programmer DiRT: Showdown Joined audio programming team as sole audio programmer for the game, using in house audio solution.
- 2009 2010, Codemasters, Game programmer DiRT3

  Created a data driven component based game system with support for replay and network serialisation. Prototyped and developed USP Gymkhana game mode.
- 2008 2009, Codemasters, Game programmer Colin McRae: DiRT2 Created the career progression system, several game modes and a framework enabling game modes to run both single player and multi player.
- 2007 2008, Codemasters, Game programmer RaceDriver: GRID Created ghost-lap recording/playback system and PC installer, refactored save systems, integrated Games For Windows..

### **Achievements**

Created in house component based game system, supporting replay and network serialisation, that has subsequently been used by multiple teams on multiple projects.

### Education

2004 - 2007, University of Skövde - Computer Game Development - Programming (Degree of Bachelor of Science with a major in Computer Science)

## Languages

Swedish (native), English (fluent), Spanish (Basic)

### References

References will be supplied on request.

## **Example of previous projects**

Please visit <a href="http://www.hentula.com">http://www.hentula.com</a> for example projects.